William Sneddon

Summary

- 14 years of experience in working with the entire software life-cycle via pragmatic approaches.
- Self-motivated and conscientious approach to roles and tasks given.
- Proven track record of learning on the job to meet client and employer demands.
- Works well individually and in teams, including technical and non-technical staff.
- Focused on delivering the correct solutions to fit the needs of clients.

Technologies Used

Languages

C#, Javascript, CSS, VB 6 MSSQL, MySQL, SQLite Java (for Android 4, Blackberry) Working knowledge of Python

Operating Systems

All major Windows since 2000 CentOS / Ubuntu Server

Data Formats

XML, JSON, EDIFACT, X12, and any other standard formats.

Frameworks

ASP.NET WebForms, MVC 5, WebAPI, Core 2.2, .NET 6

WinForms, WPF, WCF, SOAP Webservices, Windows Services.

Kendo UI, Kendo Reporting, jQuery, Django, Crystal Reports.

Source Control

Visual Sourcesafe, Subversion, Git

Experience

Senior Software Analyst - DWS Logistics Inc, Canada

2019 - 2022

- Employed to architect a replacement of the current in-house logistics platform.
- Provide technical support to infrastructure and operations teams.
- Produce technical documents of current and new systems for operations continuity.
- Design and implement integration solutions for small and Fortune 500 clients.
- Streamline and automate internal processes to reduce operational costs by \$360/day.

Senior Developer - DDL Canada, Canada

2017 - 2019

- Transferred to the Canadian office to expand client base and modernize systems.
- Led and designed new e-commerce integration with Shopify with the in-house platform.
- Created new tools to overcome platform limitations to improve user experience.
- Responsible for the support, documentation, and process streamlining of all North American clients.
- Provided occasional support to UK operations for warehouses in Belgium, Czechia, and Poland.

Technical Lead - Data Driven Logistics, UK

- 2015 2017
- Provided systems design for new projects or major product enhancements.
- Produced technical specifications, schemas, and designs.
- Mentored individuals within the company, providing a point of contact for help.
- Enforced best practices and standards as outlined by the Technical Director.
- Worked with Infrastructure Manager to implement/enhance systems architecture.

Systems Developer - Data Driven Logistics, UK

2012 - 2015

- Implemented order track and trace systems using in-house framework.
- Migrated clients from the Anoto digital pen ecosystem to bespoke replacements.
- Refactored the main application logic of the bespoke WMS for clients based in BE and PL.
- Wrote EDI interfaces, web services, SQL CLR functions for client systems and external haulers.
- Supported 24/7 client operations alongside colleagues in Canada.

Senior Developer - Magicomm, UK

2011 - 2012

- Maintained and consolidated infrastructure on Amazon EC2
- Produced technical requirements, quotations, and documentation
- Helped mentor new developers
- Because responsible for 3rd line support.

Developer - Magicomm, UK

2008 - 2011

- Created web applications for handwriting recognition using Anoto digital pen system using C#
- Created internal tools for testing and automation.
- Maintained existing mobile apps on Blackberry, WinCE and created the Android App (2.2)
- Provided integration endpoints and 1st and 2nd line support.

Developer – Self Employed, UK

2007 - 2008

- Self-employed for 6 months as a PHP developer
- Contract involved using a custom PHP framework and Zend studio

Developer – Water Management Consultants, UK

2007 - 2007

- 7 months employed as a VBA and MS Access Developer
- Supported global offices with in house time sheet system that integrated with MS Great Plains
- Created the global internal forum system utilizing VB.NET learned on the job
- Provided general on-site IT support, liaised with clients for requirements.

General Assistant – The Co-operative, UK

2005 - 2006

- Shop floor assistant, stock rotation and warehouse organization
- Dealt with customer inquiries and stand in cashier and deli assistant.

IT Support Assistant – The Priory School, UK

2005 - 2005

1 month contract to assist in new infrastructure implementation during summer with existing IT team

Education

General Certificate of Education (GCE)	Shrewsbury Sixth Form (UK Post-Secondary)	2004-2006
General Certificate of Secondary Education (GCSE)	Meole Brace Secondary School (UK Secondary)	2001-2004